我们可以考虑这两个帧之间关系的另一种方式，即帧A和帧B，
Another way we can think about the relationship between these two frames, frame A and frame B,
是通过围绕空间中某个任意轴的单一旋转来关联它们。所以
is that they are related by a single rotation about some arbitrary axis in space. So, the
挑战变得确定这个旋转轴是什么，我们去的向量
challenge becomes to determine what is this axis of rotation, the vector we going
定义是v和我们要去的那个向量周围的旋转量是多少
to define is v and what is the amount of rotation around that vector, which we’re going to
叫Theta。所以问题是发现什么是v，什么是Theta，允许
call Theta. So the problem is to discover what is v, and what is Theta, that allows
我们将框架A旋转到框架B.
us to rotate frame A into frame B.
为了找到我们旋转的轴，有一个关键的观察，那就是
In order to find the axis around which we rotate there is a key observation, and that
是我们要旋转的轴必须通过旋转不变。
is that the axis around which we are going to rotate must be unchanged by the rotation.
位于旋转轴上的任何点都将通过旋转保持不变。这意味着
Any point that lies on the rotation axis will be unchanged by rotation. That implies that
旋转轴必须是矩阵R的特征向量。旋转矩阵有三个
the rotation axis must be an eigenvector of the matrix R. A rotation matrix has got three
特征向量。有一个特征向量可以保证具有真实的元素
eigenvectors. There is one eigenvector which is guaranteed to have elements that are real
数字和它对应于1的特征值。有两个复杂的特征向量和
numbers and it corresponds to the eigenvalue of 1. There are two complex eigenvectors and
它们对应于作为旋转角θ的函数的复特征值。
they correspond to complex eigenvalues which are functions of the rotation angle Theta.
为了说明这一点，我将创建一个旋转矩阵。这并不特别重要
To illustrate this, I am going to create a rotation matrix. It doesn't particularly matter
价值是什么。我将使用欧拉角创建它。0.1,0.2,0.3。那里
what the value is. I am going to create it using Euler angles. 0.1, 0.2, 0.3. And there
它是。通过绘制它，我可以看到那个方向是什么样的。在那里我们看到旋转
it is. And I can see what that orientation looks like by plotting it. There we see rotated
坐标对应于该旋转矩阵的帧。
coordinate frame corresponding to this rotation matrix.
现在，我将查看此旋转矩阵的特征值。我们在那里看到了
Now, I am going to look at the eigenvalues of this rotation matrix. We see that there
是3个特征值，我们期望它是一个3x3矩阵，最后一个特征值是相等的
are 3 eigenvalues, we'd expect that since it's a 3x3 matrix and the last eigenvalue is equal
一个。我也可以通过询问两个输出参数来查看特征向量
to one. I can look at the eigenvectors as well by asking for two output arguments from
eig功能。现在我们在矩阵v中看到，矩阵v的每列是特征向量
the eig function. And now we see in the matrix v, each column of matrix v is an eigenvector
我们对第三个特征向量感兴趣，因为第三个特征值等于
and we're interested in the third eigenvector because the third eigenvalue was equal to
一，我们可以说第三个特征向量是真实的。所有元素的虚构部分
one, and we can say that this third eigenvector is real. The imaginary part of all the elements
等于零。
are equal to zero.
为了找到旋转量以及旋转轴，我们将使用
In order to find the amount of rotation as well as the axis of rotation, we would use
工具箱函数tr2angvec并传入我们感兴趣的旋转矩阵，和
the Toolbox function tr2angvec and pass in the rotation matrix we're interested in, and
它告诉它我们需要围绕这个特定向量旋转0.44弧度。现在，
it tells it that we need a rotation of 0.44 radians around this particular vector. Now,
我可以通过提供两个输出参数将它们放入变量中;tr2angvec，
I can get it to put those into variables by providing two output arguments; tr2angvec,
并且外向变量Theta已设置为0.4466且输出变量v为
and the outward variable Theta has been set to 0.4466 and the output variable v has being
设置为将围绕其旋转的向量。
set to the vector around which that rotation would occur.
所以问题归结为找到矩阵R的特征值和特征向量。特征向量
So the problem comes down to finding the eigenvalues and eigenvectors of the matrix R. The eigenvector
对应于一个特征值的是旋转轴V并且来自复特征向量，
corresponding to the eigenvalue of one is a rotation axis V and from the complex eigenvectors,
这是Theta的一个功能，我们可以确定我们需要的旋转角度。
which are a function of Theta, we can determine the rotation angle that we require.
现在，让我们考虑我们想做反过来;我们有旋转角度Theta和
Now, let's consider we want to do the inverse; that we have the rotation angle Theta and
我们有一个我们旋转的矢量叫做v，我们想要找到旋转矩阵。
we have the vector about which we rotate called v, and we want to find the rotation matrix.
我们需要的方程是所谓的Rodriguez方程，它将R与v和Theta联系起来。
And the equation we need is the so-called Rodriguez Equation and it relates R to v and Theta.
逆操作由函数angvec2r执行，转换角度和矢量
The inverse operation is performed by the function angvec2r, converts an angle and vector
表示旋转矩阵。我传递了旋转量，然后传入向量
representation to a rotation matrix. I pass in the rotation amount and I pass in the vector
这里是旋转矩阵，它与旋转矩阵完全相同
and here is the rotation matrix, and it's exactly the same as the rotation matrix that
我开始了。
I started with.
你会注意到这里的矩阵是一个偏斜对称矩阵，这就是类型
You’ll notice that the matrix in here is a skew symmetric matrix and this is the type
我们已经遇到的矩阵，我们将会遇到其他几次
of matrix that we've encountered already, and we will encounter a few other times in
这个课程讲座。
this course of lectures.